<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>r-b-g-b</title>
    <description>it&#39;s nice to be nice</description>
    <link>http://yourdomain.com/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://yourdomain.com/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 22:49:50 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 22:49:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.4.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>How do monkeys look?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mmmm, kind of hairy, long tails, cute little bald faces? No, what I mean is how do they look &lt;em&gt;at things&lt;/em&gt;, specifically, how do they look at other monkeys. As an undergraduate at the University of Arizona, I had the extreme fortune of working under &lt;a href=&quot;http://neurology.arizona.edu/katalin-gothard-md-phd&quot;&gt;Dr. Katalin Gothard&lt;/a&gt;, who studies social and emotional processing in the amygdala using primate models. In order to understand social cognition in primates, the &lt;a href=&quot;http://gothard.wix.com/gothard_lab&quot;&gt;Gothard lab&lt;/a&gt; showed monkeys lots and lots of pictures of other monkeys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Monkeys, like humans, communicate their emotions and intentions through eye contact and distinct, stereotyped facial expressions. And just like humans, all monkeys have their own more or less wonderful personalities, which are to some degree revealed in the path that their eyes trace as they scan a social scene. In humans, direct eye contact is often regarded as a sign of confidence. The same is true in monkeys. The difference is that, while displaying confidence as a human might help you make a great impression at your job interview, displaying confidence as a monkey will get you your monkey ass handed to you (unless you are the alpha monkey, and I’m sure you would be). Almost all neuropsychiatric disorders have some effect on scanpath patterns, for example individuals with autism will spend less time looking at facial features.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I developed ways to analyze these eye movements in order to understand how monkeys explored the faces of other monkeys. You can read about the study and see cool images of monkey faces in our article &lt;a href=&quot;http://journal.frontiersin.org/article/10.3389/neuro.08.050.2009/abstract&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;Individual differences in scanpaths correspond with serotonin transporter genotype and behavioral phenotype in rhesus monkeys (&lt;em&gt;Macaca mulatta&lt;/em&gt;)&lt;/a&gt; published in Frontiers in Behavioral Neuroscience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 25 Oct 2015 21:36:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/science/2015/10/25/how-do-monkeys-look.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/science/2015/10/25/how-do-monkeys-look.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>science</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Mapping diversity in the Bay Area</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In September 2014, some fascinating work from the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.coopercenter.org/&quot;&gt;Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service&lt;/a&gt; made the rounds on the internet. The &lt;a href=&quot;http://demographics.coopercenter.org/DotMap/&quot;&gt;Racial Dot Map&lt;/a&gt; project accomplished the impressive feat of generating a map of the United States made of of dots. Not just any dots though. Each dot represents (roughly) the residence of a single US citizen, color coded by that person’s race. In addition to being lovely to look at, the map reveals some interesting patterns of how people of different races live together (or in some cases, live very far apart from each other).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One thing I really love about the Bay Area is how diverse it is, and I became curious about what these data would show about my community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Racial Dot Map makes it very obvious where certain races are concentrated, and to some extent, it points out areas where one or two races predominate. But I wanted to visually explore something slightly different; I wanted visualize diversity &lt;em&gt;itself&lt;/em&gt;. So instead of splotches of color that represent the presence of individual races, areas would be color coded by how homogeneous or heterogeneous they were. Consider an area containing 100 people. If that area contained 100 white people, it would have the same score as if it had 100 Hispanic people, the lowest possible diversity score. If it had 50 black people and 50 Asian people, it would attain a higher score, but the same as if it had with 50 white people and 50 Asian people. It would attain the highest possible diversity score when it had an even split of all the races recorded by the US census: 20 white people, 20 black people, 20 Asian people, 20 Hispanic people, and 20 “other race” people (an unfortunate category, I know). I analyzed the diversity of census tracts, which contain on average about 4000 people in this sample.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the results: dark regions represent places with high diversity. In broad strokes, the East Bay is most diverse (yeeeeee), followed by SF and North Bay. If you want to delve a bit deeper into the demographics underlying the diversity index in a census tract, you can click on the little dot in the center of the tract to pop up the breakdown. For example, in 2010 my neighborhood had 3716 people, 1256 White, 1163 Black, 750 Hispanic, and 313 Asian and 234 other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/resources/bayarea-diversity-choropleth.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;float:right; font-size:80%&quot;&gt;view full screen&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;/resources/bayarea-diversity-choropleth.html&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;500px&quot; style=&quot;border:none&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested, you can check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://nbviewer.ipython.org/github/r-b-g-b/r-b-g-b.github.io/blob/master/_notebooks/bay-area-diversity-notebook.ipynb&quot;&gt;my Jupyter notebook&lt;/a&gt; describing exactly how I generated this map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d like to revisit this someday with a smarter measure of diversity. The index I came up with is blind to data outside of an individual census tract. Most people leave their census tracts every once in a while, so capturing larger-scale diversity would make this measure more realistic. For example, even the least diverse places in the Bay Area are probably just a 20 minute drive away from very diverse areas. A better metric would probably include something like, how large of a radius would you have to draw around your census tract to find as many people of non-predominant races as that tract has of its predominant race. For example, if my tract has 1000 Hispanic people, how big of an circle would I have to include around my tract to find 1000 non-Hispanic people? A measure like that, one that includes a concept of distance, would probably go much further towards capturing how diverse a place really feels.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 23:00:02 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/projects/data/geospatial/2015/10/20/racial-diversity-map.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/projects/data/geospatial/2015/10/20/racial-diversity-map.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
        <category>data</category>
        
        <category>geospatial</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cocktail Part A</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In July 2015, friend and composer Richard Warp and I set out to make an installation for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mainlymozart.org/mozart-and-the-mind/mozart-the-mind-the-prodigal-years/&quot;&gt;Mozart and the Mind&lt;/a&gt; conference. Our goal was to develop software that would algorithmically transform a conversation into a unique musical composition in real-time. For computer music, I had always turned to Max/MSP, but felt that it’s building-block style made it difficult to work in more conventional program flow, data analysis, and machine learning. That’s when I discovered the fantastic python module &lt;a href=&quot;http://ajaxsoundstudio.com/software/pyo/&quot;&gt;pyo&lt;/a&gt;, a library for real-time audio synthesis. I am planning on writing a blog post detailing my exploits, but for now, you can at least check out the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artist statement:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Conversation is the heart of the cocktail party. Through conversation we share our ideas and stories, and we mix our voices in an ever-changing sonic scene. Spoken language facilitates this mixture in it two ways: it is semantic: a vessel for thought, communication of abstract ideas, poetry, scientific concepts. As a semantic entity, words enable people to gather in the social plane, a shared and collaborative mental space. Speech is also sensory: rhythmic, tonal, and musical. Each person’s voice is uniquely theirs, immediately and reliably signifying the individual who produced the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In an age that has adopted text as the de facto standard for communication, we often experience the message without the music, but voice sans message has its own allure. You may have encountered it, perhaps as a child in bed, hearing the murmurs of your parents in the next room. Or perhaps as a traveller in a foreign country, overhearing voices conversing in an unfamiliar language. When words are stripped of their literal meaning, their music elevates to the forefront of our attention.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In this installation, we turn a spotlight onto this music and to the shared social space that it inhabits. Four “performers” equipped with portable EEG and voice recorders will engage in friendly cocktail party conversation. EEG and vocal output will stream to our base station, which will analyze the presence and flow of attention in this ad hoc social network. Utterances will be sampled, their linguistic meaning removed, and their musical features enhanced. An algorithm will layer and persist the samples according to the significance of their source in the social plane. By pointing out the musicality of language, we hope to convey the seed of prodigy in us all.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is one conversation, which we recorded during a demonstration for the course &lt;em&gt;EE 16B. Designing Information Devices and Systems II&lt;/em&gt; at UC Berkeley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;60%&quot; height=&quot;150&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/229330702&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is still under active development. We will present it in October at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.spectrumnyc.com/&quot;&gt;Spectrum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Oct 2015 18:22:15 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://yourdomain.com/projects/music/2015/10/19/cocktail-part-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://yourdomain.com/projects/music/2015/10/19/cocktail-part-a.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>projects</category>
        
        <category>music</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
